Guide to the Gay Wilson Allen Papers, 1801-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Walt Whitman Materials Series, 1827-1988 and undated
  - Commemorations and Societies Subseries
    - Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building, 1931-1962? (Box 10)
    - Conferences and Lectures, 1955-1988 (Box 10)
    - Dinners, 1898-1959 (Box 10)
    - Exhibitions, 1897-1982, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Huntington Historical Society, 1948-1950 (Box 10)
    - Lausanne Conference, undated (Box 10)
    - Leaves of Grass Centennial:
      - Letters, 1954-1956 (Box 10)
      - Clippings, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
      - Observances, 1954-1955? (Box 10)
    - Walt Whitman Birthplace Association:
      - By-Laws and Reports, 1950-1981? (Box 10)
      - Clippings, 1936-1977? (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1963? (Box 10)
      - Pictures, 1943-1957? (Box 10)
      - Printed Materials, 1949-1958 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954-1974 (Box 10)
    - Walt Whitman:
      - Bridge, 1955-1957 (Box 10)
      - Fellowship, 1895-1928 (Box 10)
      - Foundation:
        - Bulletins, 1948-1954 (Box 10)
        - Correspondence, 1950-1957? (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 1928-1968? (Box 10)
      - Society of America, 1940-1945? (Box 10)
    - Whitman:
      - Mausoleum restoration, 1974 (Box 10)
      - Schoolhouse, 1927-1962 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1919-1984 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence Subseries
    - Brown, Lewis Kirk, 1963-1927 (Box 10)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1842-1890 (Box 10)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1855 (Box 10)
    - Ferguson, David, 1863 (Box 10)
    - Gosse, Edmund, undated (Box 10)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane, 1887-1890 (Box 10)
    - O'Connor, Ellen, 1863-1876 (Box 10)
    - O'Connor, William Douglas, 1864-1881 (Box 10)
    - Osgood, James R., and Co., 1881-1882 (Box 10)
    - Price, Abby H., 1863-1869 (Box 10)
    - Sawyer, Thomas P., 1863-1864 (Box 10)
    - Stafford, Harry, 1876-1881 (Box 10)
    - Thayer and Eldridge, 1860 (Box 10)
    - Whitman, letters about, 1866-1942 (Box 10)
    - Whitman family letters, 1859-1906? (Box 10)
    - Whitman, Louisa, 1860-1873, (8 folders) (Box 10)
  - Pictures Subseries (Box 11)
    - 1860-1955, undated, (6 folders) (Box 11)
  - Popular Culture Subseries
    - Art, 1914-1968? (Box 11)
    - Drama, 1951-1982 (Box 11)
    - Music, 1901-1981? (Box 11)
    - Philately, 1940-1956? (Box 11)
    - Radio and television, 1944-1976 (Box 11)
    - Religion, 1919-1984? (Box 11)
  - Writings Subseries
    - Abridgment and Abstract... Lyman E. Munson, 1868 (Box 11)
    - American Primer, undated (Box 11)
    - Annotations and Readings, undated (Box 11)
    - As One By One Withdraw the Lofty Actions, n. d. (Box 11)
    - As I Sit in the Twilight Late, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Autobiographical note, undated (Box 11)
    - Contemporary newspaper articles, 1879-1884 "The Dead Tenor," 1884 (Box 11)
    - Diary notes, 1964-1883? (Box 11)
    - Drum Taps, 1966-1961? (Box 11)
    - Dix-Huitieme Presidence, 1926 (Box 11)
    - Facts in the Matter of Worthington... n. d. (Box 11)
    - Father Taylor and Oratory, 1887 (Box 11)
    - Fragments, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Horse Race at Jamaica, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Inscription, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Introduction to the London Edition, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Little Bells Last Night, 1861 (Box 11)
    - Old-Age Echoes and Some Personal and Old Age Memoranda, 1891 (Box 11)
    - An Old Man's Recitatives, 1890-1891 (Box 11)
    - Once I Passed Through a Populous City, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Opinions:
      - Cremation, 1875 (Box 11)
      - Misuse of Gifts to Soldiers, n. d. (Box 11)
      - Personal appearance, undated (Box 11)
    - Osceola, undated (Box 11)
    - Passage to India, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Personalism, 1868 (Box 11)
    - The Poetry of the Future, n. d (Box 11)
    - A Riddle Song, undated (Box 11)
    - Rise, Lurid Stars, undated (Box 11)
    - Slavery, 1860? (Box 11)
    - Some 'Leaves of Grass,' undated (Box 11)
    - Song of Myself, 1854? (Box 11)
    - Sunday Restrictions, 1854 (Box 11)
    - Taine's History of English Literature, 1871-1957 (Box 11)
    - A Thought on Shakespeare, 1886 (Box 11)
    - The Tomb Blossoms, undated (Box 11)
    - The Unexpected, 1890 (Box 11)
    - A Voice from Death, 1899 (Box 11)
    - Walt Whitman's Last, 1891 (Box 11)
    - Warble for Lilac-Time, 1870 (Box 11)
    - With All the Gifts America, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Wood Odors, 1960 (Box 11)
    - A Word About Tennyson, 1887 (Box 11)
    - You Lingering Sparse Leaves of Me, n. d. (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries
    - Anderson, R. B., undated (Box 11)
    - Bibliography, n. d. (Box 11)
    - Brochures, 1955-1975 (Box 11)
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Carpenter, Edward, 1877-1910, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - The Evening Tattler, 1842 (Box 11)
    - Feinberg, Charles E., 1952-1967? (Box 11)
    - Homosexuality, 1954-1956 (Box 11)
    - Libraries with Whitman Collections, 1908-1972? (Box 11)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane, 1882-1960, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Southold, Long Island, 1827-1984 (Box 11)
    - Theft of Walt Whitman's Commonplace Book, 1955 (Box 11)
    - Traubel, Horace, 1902-1981? (Box 11)
    - Trivia, 1863-1976? (Box 11)
    - Verwey, Albert, undated (Box 11)
    - Whitman Bibliographies, 1919-1955 (Box 11)
    - Whitman Bibliography Conference, 1948 (Box 11)
    - Whitman in Foreign Countries, 1954-1971? (Box 11)
    - Wills, 1873-1884? (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-1955? (Box 11)
- Walt Whitman Scholars Series, 1880-1975 and undated
  Subseries: Evie Allison Allen Papers, Charles N. Elliot Papers, Emory Holloway Papers, Peter Mitilineos Papers, Hans Reisinger Papers, and Henry Scholey Saunders Papers.
  - Evie Allison Allen Papers Subseries
    - Kaj Monk, n. d., (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Spring Comes So Slowly, undated, (8 folders) (Box 12)
    - Walt Whitman:
      - Page Proof, 1950, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1951, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Walt Whitman in Person, 1956?, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 12)
  - Charles N. Elliot Papers Subseries
    - 1917-1920 (Box 12)
  - Emory Holloway Papers Subseries
    - 1918-1961, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Peter Mitilineos Papers Subseries
    - Correspondence:
      - Allen, Gay Wilson, 1972-1975? (Box 12)
      - Jannacone, Pasquale, 1955-1956? (Box 12)
    - Writings:
      - Passage to Attica, 1973? (Box 12)
      - A Phyllum of Chloë, undated (Box 12)
      - Poetry and the 'Organic Form', n. d. (Box 12)
    - Translations:
      - The Esthetics of Edgar Allen Poe, 1973?, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - The Last Invocation, n. d. (Box 12)
      - Walt Whitman's Poetry..., Draft, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Translations: (Box 13)
      - Walt Whitman's Poetry.... Manuscript, 1972-1973?, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Hans Reisiger Papers Subseries
    - 1954-1955, undated, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Henry Scholey Saunders Papers Subseries
    - Bibliographies:
      - Bibliography and Criticism, 1941 (Box 13)
      - Whitman Music, 1940? (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1922, 1947 (Box 13)
    - Printed material, 1880-1947?, (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1920 (Box 13)
- Writings Series, 1898-1988.
  Contains copies of Allen's essays and book reviews, and the various drafts and production stages of several of his books.
  - Address on Receiving the Tamiment Institute Book Award, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Biblical Echoes in Whitman's Works, 1934 (Box 13)
  - Calamus-Leaves, 1969, undated, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Carl Sandburg, undated (Box 13)
  - "Centennial of Leaves of Grass," 1955 (Box 13)
  - Eccentric Professors, 1962 (Box 13)
  - "Editing The Writings of Walt Whitman," 1962 (Box 13)
  - Humor in Emerson, n. d. (Box 13)
  - The Iconography of Walt Whitman, n. d. (Box 13)
  - Foreword to Letters of Ellen Tucker Emerson, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Melville and His World:
    - Illustrations, 1970-1976? (Box 13)
    - Text, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Mr. Ohsava, Discoverer of 'Order of Universe', 1950-1951, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - A New Look at Emerson and Science, 1975 (Box 23)
  - The New Walt Whitman Handbook: Manuscript Copy I and 2, 1974, (7 folders) (Box 23)
  - The New Walt Whitman Handbook: (Box 14)
    - Galleys, 1974-1975?, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Page Proofs, 1975, (4 folders) (Box 14)
    - Blues, 1975, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - November Boughs and Other Prose, 1949-1952 (Box 14)
  - Passage to More Than India, 1951-1952? (Box 14)
  - Pluralism, undated (Box 14)
  - Radio Scripts, 1955, undated (Box 14)
  - A Reader's Guide to Walt Whitman, 1969-1970, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - "Regarding the 'Publication' of the First Leaves of Grass," 1956 (Box 14)
  - Reviews, 1945-1974 (Box 14)
  - The Solitary Singer:
    - Proposal, 1951? (Box 14)
    - First draft, 1950?, (9 folders) (Box 14)
    - Second draft, 1952?, (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - The Solitary Singer: (Box 15)
    - Second draft, 1952?, (4 folders) (Box 15)
    - Manuscript copy 1, 1954?, (5 folders) (Box 15)
    - Manuscript copy 2, 1954?, (5 folders) (Box 15)
    - Illustrations, 1955?, (9 folders) (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1967?, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Reviews, 1955 (Box 15)
  - Speaking Personally, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Specimen Days and Other Prose, 1949-1952? (Box 16)
  - St. John de Crevecoeur:
    - Correspondence, 1922, 1985-1987 (Box 16)
    - Drafts, 1986?, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Manuscript, 1986?, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 16)
    - Reviews, 1987-1988? (Box 16)
  - Studies in Leaves of Grass, undated (Box 16)
  - The Two Poets of "Leaves of Grass," 1968-1969? (Box 16)
  - Waldo Emerson:
    - Research files, undated, (6 folders) (Box 16)
    - Drafts:
      - Front Matter, 1975-1979? (Box 16)
      - Chapters 1-6, 1975-1979, (6 folders) (Box 16)
  - Waldo Emerson: Drafts, Chapters 7-23, (15 folders) (Box 17)
  - Waldo Emerson: (Box 18)
    - Drafts:
      - Chapters 24-28, 1975-1979, (5 folders) (Box 18)
      - Notes, 1975-1979, (9 folders) (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous, 1975-1979? (Box 18)
    - Manuscript, 1980?, (7 folders) (Box 18)
    - Galleys, 1980?, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - Waldo Emerson: Illustrations, 1934-1978, undated, (3 folders) (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman Abroad: 1945-1954, (3 folders) (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman and.... undated (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman Bibliography, 1918-1934, 1935 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman Foundation Bulletin, 1948-1954 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman in Comparative Literature, 1943 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman Handbook: Reviews, 1945-1946? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman and Jules Michelet, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman's 'Long Journey' Motif, 1939 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman as Man, Poet, and Legend, 1961-1967 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman the Man, 1955 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman--Nationalist or Proletarian? 1937 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman's Passage to India, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman as Philosopher, 1930? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman's Poems: Miscellaneous, 1953-1958? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman's Posthumous Fame, 1947-1955? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman's Reception in Scandinavia, 1946? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman: Reviews, Notices, Fan Letters, 1959-1961? (Box 19)
  - Walt Whitman and Stoicism, n. d. (Box 19)
  - Whitman Abroad, 1949 (Box 19)
  - Whitman and the Influence of Space on American Literature, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Whitman and Michelet--Continued, 1973? (Box 19)
  - William James
    - Research files, 1898-1969? (Box 19)
    - Notecards, n. d. (Box 19)
    - Manuscripts: (Box 20)
      - Draft, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - Prefatory material, undated (Box 20)
      - Chapters 1-21, undated, (7 folders) (Box 20)
      - Notes, n. d. (Box 20)
    - Page proofs, 1967?, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Illustrations, 1962-1963 (Box 20)
    - Excerpts in Parapsychology, 1967 (Box 20)
    - Review, 1967 (Box 20)
  - With Faulkner in Japan, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Writings of Walt Whitman:
    - Center for Editions of American Authors/Conference on Whitman Edition, 1959-1968 (Box 20)
    - Announcements, 1955-1983 (Box 20)
  - The Young Whitman, 1955 (Box 20)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1925-1975 and undated
  - Fragments of writings?, undated (Box 20)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, undated (Box 20)
  - Notes:
    - Gerald Manley Hopkins, undated (Box 20)
    - Notes on 20th-century American poets, with three typed poems by Wendell Berry, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Notecards, n. d. (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1925-1975? (Box 20)
- Oversize Materials
  - Miscellaneous oversize materials re: Whitman and Printed Materials and Manuscripts series (Box 23)
  - Oversize Correspondence Series, 1931-1963 (Box 22)
  - Oversize Clifton Joseph Furness Papers Series (Box 22)
    - Clara Barrus Papers Subseries
      - Research Files: John Burroughs (Box 22)
      - Correspondence: Charles Wesley Eldridge (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1936-1944 (Box 22)
      - Printed material: The Conservator, 1905-1919 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence Subseries
      - Vrionides, Christos, 1926-1941? (Box 23)
  - Oversize Printed Materials and Literary Manuscripts Series
    - Clippings: The Long-Islander, Whitman Papers, 1959-1976 (Box 22)
    - Essays and offprints: Titherington, 1895-1896? (Box 22)
    - Clippings: The Long Islander, 1961-1979 (Box 24)
    - Clippings: Russian newspapers and magazines, 1955 (Box 24)
    - Clippings: Asani Weekly Edition issue, 1925 (Box 24)
    - Clippings: Brooklyn Daily Eagle Sunday issue, 1936 (Box 24)
    - Clippings: Revista Shell, May 1958 (Box 24)
    - Walt Whitman festival posters, 1969 and 1980 (Box 24)
  - Oversize Scrapbooks Series (Box 21)
  - Oversize Walt Whitman Materials Series
    - Commemorations and Societies Subseries, 1949-1988, undated (Box 22)
    - Correspondence Subseries
      - "Chronological Correspondence," 1867-1889 (Box 22)
    - Popular Culture Subseries
      - Pictures, 1860-1955? (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous: Congressional Record, 1942, Feb. 12 (Box 22)
    - Writings Subseries
      - 1841-1950? (Box 22)
      - 1801-1970?, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Oversize Walt Whitman Scholars Series (Box 22)
  - Oversize Writings Series (Box 22)
    - Melville and His World: Illustrations, 1921, n. d. (Box 22)
    - The Solitary Singer: (Box 22)
      - Illustrations, 1954-1966? (Box 22)
      - Reviews, 1955 (Box 22)
  - Oversize Miscellaneous Series
    - Awards for The Solitary Singer, 1955 (Box 22)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, undated (Box 22)
    - Phonograph record, Jean Eichelberger Ivey, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Walden Mss., 1854? (Box 22)
- Accessions 95-095 and 95-100
  This unprocessed accession of professional correspondence, subject files, miscellaneous files and loose materials was added to the Gay Wilson Allen Papers in 1995 and is open for research.
  - Subject Files and Correspondence Files A-K (Box 1)
    - Albrecht (Box 1)
    - Alegria (Box 1)
    - G. W. Allen (Box 1)
    - American Literary Association, American Literature Section (Box 1)
    - American Scholar (Box 1)
    - C. Anderson, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - American National Biography (Box 1)
    - V. Andrews (Box 1)
    - Asselineau, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - BAC (Box 1)
    - BAK (Box 1)
    - Evelyn Barish (Box 1)
    - Barzun (Box 1)
    - BC Research (Box 1)
    - Joseph Beaver (Box 1)
    - H. Bergman, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - H. Blodgett (Box 1)
    - Susan Brown (Box 1)
    - Matthew Bruccoli (Box 1)
    - C. Budd (Box 1)
    - F. Burns (Box 1)
    - H. Burns (Box 1)
    - Burnshaw (Box 1)
    - Bill Butts (Box 1)
    - Edwin H. Cady (Box 1)
    - Calgary (Box 1)
    - Camden (Whitman) (Box 1)
    - D.B. Carpenter (Box 1)
    - Carybe (Box 1)
    - Central Memorial Society (Box 1)
    - Fred Chappell (Box 1)
    - Chari (Box 1)
    - Chicago (University English Department) (Box 1)
    - China (Box 1)
    - Chistova (Box 1)
    - Citrus College (Box 1)
    - V. Clemente (Box 1)
    - Cobblestone Publishing (Box 1)
    - Copyright (Box 1)
    - Cornell (Box 1)
    - Culton (Box 1)
    - Lois Dawson (Box 1)
    - John Ditsky (Box 1)
    - DLB (Box 1)
    - Drabrowski (Box 1)
    - Duke (Box 1)
    - Leon Edel (Box 1)
    - Emerson (Box 1)
    - Erkela (Box 1)
    - Erkkila (Box 1)
    - Eury (Box 1)
    - Eve (Box 1)
    - Eye Center (Box 1)
    - Fahey (Box 1)
    - Mort Frank (Box 1)
    - Freud (Box 1)
    - G.G. Fromm (Box 1)
    - Funk and Wagnalls (Box 1)
    - Georgia (University of) (Box 1)
    - Gibson (Box 1)
    - Susan Gilbert (Box 1)
    - Gimbel (Box 1)
    - C. Gohdes (Box 1)
    - Golden, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - R. Gozzi (Box 1)
    - Greenspan (Box 1)
    - Grieer (Box 1)
    - Grohskopf (Box 1)
    - Grunzweiss (Box 1)
    - Harriss (Box 1)
    - Haugen (Box 1)
    - Hemlock Society (Box 1)
    - P. H. Hill (Box 1)
    - W. Hill (Box 1)
    - C. Hollis (Box 1)
    - Holy Cow (Box 1)
    - Bill Holm (Box 1)
    - R. Hone (Box 1)
    - S. Horner (Box 1)
    - Hotchkiss (Box 1)
    - Iaupe (Box 1)
    - India (Box 1)
    - Iowa (University of), (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Eric Jacobson (Box 1)
    - Japanese Letters (Box 1)
    - S. J. Kahn (Box 1)
    - Kaplan (Box 1)
    - Kazin (Box 1)
    - Vincent Kenny (Box 1)
  - Subject Files and Correspondence Files K-Z a (Box 2)
    - Kent State (Box 2)
    - Bob King (Box 2)
    - J. Krieg (Box 2)
    - Library of Congress (Box 2)
    - Livingston (Box 2)
    - L.R. Lorant (Box 2)
    - Loving (Box 2)
    - Michael Lynch (Box 2)
    - Marks (Box 2)
    - Anne and Bill Maxson (Box 2)
    - Maxwell (Box 2)
    - E. Miller (Box 2)
    - Miyoshi (Box 2)
    - William Moore (Box 2)
    - Robert Morgan (Box 2)
    - Mulder (Box 2)
    - F. Murphy (Box 2)
    - Museum of City (New York) (Box 2)
    - Joel Myerson (Box 2)
    - Nakada (Box 2)
    - Nambiar (Box 2)
    - Nandyal ( India) (Box 2)
    - National Association of Scholars (Box 2)
    - NCSU (Box 2)
    - Nolan (Box 2)
    - Nurk (Box 2)
    - NYU English Department (Box 2)
    - Nuzum (Box 2)
    - Jackie Pace (Box 2)
    - Marie Clara Paro (Box 2)
    - Pollak (Box 2)
    - K. Price (Box 2)
    - D. Reynolds (Box 2)
    - Schyberg (Box 2)
    - H. Sebastian (Box 2)
    - G. Sill (Box 2)
    - L. Simon (Box 2)
    - State University of New York (Box 2)
    - S. Stepanchev (Box 2)
    - Strassburg (Box 2)
    - A. Studdard (Box 2)
    - Suhre (Box 2)
    - Summersgill (Box 2)
    - Tennessee University Press (Box 2)
    - N. Teraoka (Box 2)
    - That Strange Year (Box 2)
    - W. Thomas (Box 2)
    - Thorson (Box 2)
    - Tobias (Box 2)
    - Vance (Box 2)
    - Robert White (Box 2)
    - William Whit Whitman, (6 folders) (Box 2)
    - Lois Whitter (Box 2)
    - L. Wolfson (Box 2)
    - Jim Woodress (Box 2)
    - Phil Young (Box 2)
    - Youngblood. (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Subject Files A-L (Box 3)
    - Alcott (Box 3)
    - American Art (Box 3)
    - American Book Company (Box 3)
    - American Civilization ( NYU) (Box 3)
    - American Art ( NYU) (Box 3)
    - American Literary Criticism (anthology) (Box 3)
    - American Literature Reserve List (Box 3)
    - American Poetry Since 1900 (Box 3)
    - American Society (Box 3)
    - American Studies Newsletter (Box 3)
    - J. W. Anderson (Box 3)
    - Sherwood Anderson (Box 3)
    - Atlantic Monthly (Box 3)
    - Auden (on D. H. Lawrence) (Box 3)
    - Auden ( Christian Tragedy) (Box 3)
    - W. H. Auden, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Sylvia Beach (Box 3)
    - Saul Bellow (Box 3)
    - S.V. Benet (Box 3)
    - John Berryman (Box 3)
    - Biography (Box 3)
    - Book Binders (Box 3)
    - Book Reviews ( NYTBR) (Box 3)
    - Borges (Box 3)
    - Catherine D. Bowen (Box 3)
    - Warren Bower (Box 3)
    - Andrew Brandes (Box 3)
    - Broadcast Music (Box 3)
    - Broderie (Box 3)
    - Bryant (Box 3)
    - John Burroughs (Box 3)
    - J. Cabell (Box 3)
    - G. W. Cable (Box 3)
    - Capek (Box 3)
    - F. Carpenter (Box 3)
    - Will Cather (Box 3)
    - Center for Editions (Box 3)
    - Chicago University Press (Box 3)
    - S. Clemens (Box 3)
    - Cliche (Box 3)
    - T. Cole (Box 3)
    - Colophon (Box 3)
    - Columbia University (Box 3)
    - Comp. Lit. (Box 3)
    - Contemporary Literature (Box 3)
    - Coope (Box 3)
    - Copyright (Box 3)
    - Country Wife (summary) (Box 3)
    - Cowley (Box 3)
    - H. Crane (Box 3)
    - Stephen Crane (Box 3)
    - Crevecoeur (Box 3)
    - Criticism (Box 3)
    - E. E. Cummings (Box 3)
    - Deism (Box 3)
    - Dixie (Box 3)
    - Emily Dickinson (Box 3)
    - Dos Passos (Box 3)
    - Drama (Box 3)
    - T. Dreiser (Box 3)
    - Dualism (Box 3)
    - Ducation ( W. Lippman) (Box 3)
    - T. S. Eliot, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Emerson Seminar (Box 3)
    - Emerson, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - English 2810 ( 1800-1860) (Box 3)
    - English 2914 (Literary Biography) (Box 3)
    - English 2920 (Poetics) (Box 3)
    - Etzler (Box 3)
    - Fuller (Box 3)
    - G41.2830 (Box 3)
    - Galler (poems) (Box 3)
    - H. Garland (Box 3)
    - Graduate School (thesis) (Box 3)
    - Robert Graves (Box 3)
    - MSS Greenberg (Box 3)
    - Grierson (Box 3)
    - Guggenheim (Box 3)
    - Harper (Box 3)
    - Hawthorne, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - H. H. Hayne (Box 3)
    - Hegel (Box 3)
    - Hemingway (Box 3)
    - Holmes (Box 3)
    - Howells (Box 3)
    - Hudson River School (Box 3)
    - Aldous Huxley (Box 3)
    - Imagery, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Impressionism (Box 3)
    - Irony (Box 3)
    - Irving (Box 3)
    - Henry James, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Jarrell (Box 3)
    - R. Jeffers (Box 3)
    - Jefferson (Box 3)
    - Journal of English and Germanic Philology (Box 3)
    - James Joyce (Box 3)
    - Kmickerboskers (Box 3)
    - Davies Langton (Box 3)
    - Language (Box 3)
    - Lanier (Box 3)
    - Late 19th Century American Literature (Box 3)
    - Sinclair Lewis (Box 3)
    - Library (Box 3)
    - Literary Biography (Box 3)
    - Literary Historians (Box 3)
    - Jack London (Box 3)
    - Longfellow (Box 3)
    - Lowell, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Subject Files M-Z (Box 4)
    - Masters (Box 4)
    - Matthiesen (Box 4)
    - Maugham (Box 4)
    - Melville, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Melville Society (Box 4)
    - Arthur Miller (Box 4)
    - Henry Miller, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Moby Dick (Box 4)
    - Monograph Committee (Box 4)
    - M. Moore (Box 4)
    - Mystics (Box 4)
    - National Literature 1837-1855 (Box 4)
    - Nature (Box 4)
    - Naturalism (Box 4)
    - Negro (Box 4)
    - Neurotic Personality (Box 4)
    - New York Review (Box 4)
    - New York Times (Box 4)
    - Niebuhr (Box 4)
    - Nietzsche (Box 4)
    - Norris (Box 4)
    - Novel in America (Box 4)
    - O'Neill (Box 4)
    - Paine (Box 4)
    - T. Parker (Box 4)
    - C.S. Peirce (Box 4)
    - Piranesi (Box 4)
    - Poe (Box 4)
    - E. Porkman (Box 4)
    - Pound (Box 4)
    - Pychoanalysis and Art (Box 4)
    - Puritanism (Box 4)
    - J. C. Ransom (Box 4)
    - Ratner (Box 4)
    - Rhyme (Box 4)
    - E. A. Robinson (Box 4)
    - Romanticism (Box 4)
    - Rousseau (Box 4)
    - Salinger (Box 4)
    - Sandburg (Box 4)
    - Santyanna (Box 4)
    - W. Saroyan (Box 4)
    - Scholasticism (Box 4)
    - Semantics (Box 4)
    - Senegal (Box 4)
    - Shopira (Box 4)
    - Southern Literature (Box 4)
    - Stephen Spender (Box 4)
    - Stein (Box 4)
    - Steinbeck (Box 4)
    - Steve Stepanchev (Box 4)
    - H. B. Stone (Box 4)
    - Style, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Edward Taylor (Box 4)
    - Thoreau, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Times Square (Box 4)
    - Tragedy (Box 4)
    - Transcendentalism (Box 4)
    - Mark Twain (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - John Updike (Box 4)
    - Carl Van Doren (Box 4)
    - Jones Very (Box 4)
    - Warfil (Box 4)
    - Welsh Metrics (Box 4)
    - Werzeland (Box 4)
    - N. West (Box 4)
    - West (1840's) (Box 4)
    - E. Wharton (Box 4)
    - Whitman Seminar 1974-5 (Box 4)
    - Whitman, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Whittier (Box 4)
    - William Carlos Williams (Box 4)